PERSONAL INFORMATION		
Field:	Information Technology, Programming, Data Research, Data Annotation, Networking.	
Email:	robertwachirae@gmail.com	
Telephone number:	+254716028975	

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To obtain a position of responsibility that utilizes my skills and experience. Very keen to work in an environment of growth and excellence and earn a job that provides job satisfaction and self-development and helps to achieve organizational as well as personal goals.

PROFESSIONAL STRENGTHS

I am an ambitious person who has developed a responsible and mature approach to any presented situation or task. As a developer with experience in software development, I have proven web design and software development records. I have outstanding interpersonal and technological skills, allowing me to communicate with various clients. I am willing to be challenged professionally and collaborate with others to achieve the goals set. My biggest ambition is to use my technological know-how to help other individuals and organizations grow and make the world a better place. I place expertise in the following areas:

- Frontend application development: CSS | Node.js | HTML5.
- Backend application development: PHP | Java (Spring MVC).
- Database Management: MYSQL.
- Software development Methodologies: Agile, Waterfall
- · Networking skills.
- Use of Git and GitHub.
- PC Troubleshooting and maintenance.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Year	Institution	Course	Qualifications
2022	Co-operative University of Kenya	Bachelor of Science in Information Technology	2 nd Upper Class Honors.
2022	LinkedIn Learning	Programming Foundations: Web Security	Certificate
2018	Kenya College of Accountancy	Certificate of Public Account	Ongoing
2018	Kenya College of Accountancy	International Computer Driving License	Certificate
2017	Nyeri High School	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education	Certificate

WORK EXPERIENCE

August 2022 - Present: eCore Services - Data Researcher

Duties and responsibilities

- Conducting research on the internet for information as per the requirements of the client.
- Involved in data entry of information into the database.
- Data enrichment, where I participated in researching on the internet and updating the information on an existing database.
- Reviewing the information submitted and validating it, and if any errors are found, the data is cleaned.

CURRICULUM VITAE, ROBERT WACHIRA

February 2019 - Present: Freelance Software Developer

Duties and responsibilities

- I have been in the development of various websites and desktop applications as per the request of clients to their satisfaction.
- Learning various programming languages during my part-time.
- Teaching my colleagues various programming concepts while broadening my knowledge of the modules.
- Involved in programming projects that have been helpful in the collection of data and acquisition of knowledge.

November 2021 – January 2022: Technical University of Kenya – Attaché

Duties and responsibilities

- Involved in PC troubleshooting and ensured other components, such as the printers, were working efficiently and keeping track of the equipment working well during the performance audit.
- Involved in networking throughout the institution, where I was the leader of all the attachés and involved them in participating in networking cables across the buildings.
- Submitting reports of my daily attachment activities to my supervisor for approval.
- Involved in assisting the students of the institution in setting up their student portals and e-learning platforms.
- Involved in helping the institution's staff with any technical problems that they encountered.
- Involved in group projects revamping the institution's technology department website.

April 2020 - November 2020: Remotasks - Data Annotator

Duties and responsibilities

- Performed various tasks such as data collection, 2D image annotation, and segmentation, transcription, 3D image annotations, and segmentation.
- Participation in boot camps involving me in training and completing higher valued tasks within the session.
- I was involved in categorizing data on websites and text groups.

August 2019 - August 2019: Kenya National Bureau of Statistics - Enumerator

Duties and responsibilities

- I partook in training on how to use the necessary equipment and ensure that they work well on the due date.
- I administered questions and recorded the responses of those who spent the night of the due date in the area that I
 was allocated.
- I ensured I collected complete and accurate answers and captured them during the census period.
- I also undertook any delegated roles assigned to me by my supervisors.

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Ability to work efficiently under pressure.
- Ability to prioritize multiple tasks.
- Ability to lead others well.
- Ability to work with others as a team proficiently.
- Ability to carry out research work and have good negotiation skills.

CURRICULUM VITAE, ROBERT WACHIRA

REFEREES

Mr. Geoffrey Kimani Former Deputy Chief Economist Ministry of Health P.O. Box 30016-00100 Nairobi Tel: +254 721 854492

Mr. Joseph Mwangi Audit Manager Technical University of Kenya P.O. BOX 52428 – 00100, Nairobi Tel: +254733911614 Mr. Gabriel Bright Network Assistant Technical University of Kenya P.O. Box 52428 – 00100, Nairobi Tel: +254718355387